<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robust Tools on Data Science with R</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robust Tools on Data Science with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>00 :: Welcome to the class!</title>
      <link>/welcome-to-robust-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/welcome-to-robust-tools/</guid>
      <description>Before we get started, it helps to have an overview of the class. First, what is the class for?  Second, what do we hope to learn and why is this important for people who work in the social and behavioural sciences? Third, if we do want to do this class, what do we need to do to get started?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 :: Elegant data visualisation</title>
      <link>/data-visualisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-visualisation/</guid>
      <description>The course begins with an introduction to data visualisation in R using the ggplot2 package. It is assumed that this is our first encounter with R, so this section also covers many introductory topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 :: Say hello to your data</title>
      <link>/hello-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hello-data/</guid>
      <description>The second section discusses how to read data into R and how to write output to CSV files, and introduces some of the tools used to create grouped summaries of data. In this section we first encounter the &amp;lsquo;pipe&amp;rsquo; operator %&amp;gt;%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 :: Go dancing with your data</title>
      <link>/data-wrangling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-wrangling/</guid>
      <description>An introduction to data manipulation and data wrangling in R using the dplyr package. Topics covered include: extracting a subset of the data, rearranging the data, computing new variables in a data set, merging multiple data sets, and reshaping a data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 :: Literate programming in R</title>
      <link>/literate-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/literate-programming/</guid>
      <description>The fourth section in the class is built around a concrete problem: how can we build a website using R? In doing so it provides an overview of how to use R markdown and blogdown, and familiarises you with git and github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 :: How to program an aRt</title>
      <link>/programming-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming-art/</guid>
      <description>The fifth section in the course is an art class, of sorts. Notionally the goal is to build a new generative art system, but it also serves as a mechanism to introduce key programming concepts: vectors, lists, coercion, logical operations, loops and conditionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 :: Functional programming for art and science</title>
      <link>/functional-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/functional-programming/</guid>
      <description>The sixth section is also an art class, this time focused on writing functions and using the functional programming toolkit in the purrr package. There is also some art though, I promise!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topics still to come</title>
      <link>/to-be-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/to-be-continued/</guid>
      <description>The materials posted so far cover some, but not all of the content I hope to include. My &amp;lsquo;wish list&amp;rsquo; for future topics is listed here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>